### Joel Gonzalez - Page 1

# Joel Gonzalez - Curriculum Vitae

Email: bgonzale@andrew.cmu.edu - Personal Website: b-joel-gonzalez.github.io

# **Career Objectives**

Interested in electronics engineering, from systems-level design to device fabrication. Pursuing a doctorate in electrical and computer engineering, with a long-term goal of teaching and research at a university. Love of learning and helping guide others to their fullest potential.

#### **Education**

# Carnegie Mellon University — College of Engineering (CIT)

- ❖ Ph.D. Student in *Electrical and Computer Engineering* − started August '21
  - > Research Advisor: Dr. L. Richard Carley
  - > Research Interests: integrated systems design, device fabrication, rapid prototyping of computer systems, RF engineering, metrology and instrumentation
- ❖ M.S. in *Electrical and Computer Engineering*, concentration in *Integrated Systems* − May '24 University of Pennsylvania − School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS)
- ❖ M.S.E. in *Robotics* − May '21
- ❖ B.S.E. in *Computer Science*, minor in *Mathematics* − December '19

#### **Teaching Experience**

Semesters as lead TA denoted with \* and semesters online denoted with ^.

- ❖ CMU 18-429/729: Board-Level RF Systems for IoT Fall 2022\*, Fall 2023\*, Fall 2024\*
  - > Experimental laboratory course exploring RF engineering concepts, including transmission lines, antenna design, SDR, MIMO, and beamforming
- ❖ CMU − 18-540/745: *Rapid Prototyping of Computer Systems* − Spring 2023
  - ➤ Capstone project course exploring the development of an F1TENTH autonomous vehicle testing suite, partnered with Honda's 99P Labs
- ❖ UPenn ESE450/451: ESE Senior Design Fall 2019, Spring 2020^, Fall 2020\*^, Spring 2021\*^
  - > Two-part senior capstone project series for students in ESE and related majors
- ♦ UPenn ESE350/519: Embedded Systems Lab Fall 2020^, Spring 2021\*^
  - > Advanced laboratory course covering the foundations and design of embedded systems platforms, across both hardware and software levels
- ❖ UPenn ESE190/M&TSI: Introduction to Hardware/Software Lab Spring 2019, Summer 2021\*^
  - > Introductory laboratory course exploring the Arduino platform for beginners
- ♦ UPenn CIS371/501: Computer Architecture Fall 2019, Spring 2020^
  - > Advanced systems course exploring design and optimization techniques in modern computer architecture, with labs in Verilog
- ♦ UPenn CIS380/548/CIT595: *Operating Systems* Fall 2019, Spring 2020\*^, Summer 2020\*^
  - > Advanced systems course exploring design and implementation of operating systems, primarily Unix-based, in the C programming language
- ❖ UPenn CIS240/CIT593: Introduction to Computer Systems Fall 2018, Spring 2019, Summer 2019^
  - > Introductory systems course covering topics from CMOS logic gates to architecture design to operating systems programming

### Joel Gonzalez - Page 2

### Research Experience

- Novel Devices Research
  - > Started in Spring 2024
  - > Exploring nanoelectronics design and fabrication including:
    - 2D materials for bit-patterned media via scanning tunneling microscopy
    - Vertical nanostructures for gate-all-around transistors
    - In-situ construction of semiconductor devices within a plasma FIB scope
- ❖ Hacker Fab: Open-Source Semiconductor Fabrication Laboratory
  - > Joined research lab at its inception in Spring 2023
  - > Designing an open-source lab on CMU's campus, capable of fabricating CMOS transistors from silicon using a custom-built maskless photolithography stepper
  - ➤ Goal is to fabricate a functional NMOS transistor with 10um gate width by May 2023, then hoping to expand the capabilities of the lab to CMOS and then entire integrated circuits
  - ➤ Planning to use the lab space for a new course in Fall 2023 that will allow students to fabricate their own ICs on-campus, as well as to continue the development of the lab's machines and processes
  - ➤ Links to the lab's <u>website</u>, where resources and updates are provided
- ❖ FLOCI: Lab-On-Chip Interferometer
  - ➤ Joined research team in Spring 2023
  - > Developing an RFIC to measure ferromagnetic resonance using a novel on-chip solution, removing the necessity of a VNA-FMR
  - > Using a transmission line differential pair to detect the presence of nanoparticles as an amplitude-modulated signal, which is then amplified and downconverted to be processed off-chip
  - > Working on simulating and refining the transmission line design using Ansys Electronics Desktop software, as well as helping design test infrastructure
  - > RFIC taped out in May 2023 using TSMC 28nm PDK
  - > Planning to test and evaluate chip in early 2024 and publish results
- ❖ MIT Lincoln Lab: Advanced RF Techniques & Systems
  - Summer 2023 research intern working on RF systems design and analysis for communication systems
  - > Internship completed as part of employer sponsorship via GEM Fellowship

### Joel Gonzalez - Page 3

### **Activities, Awards, and Recognitions**

- Recipient of the 2017 Penn Undergraduate Research Mentoring (PURM) Grant
- ❖ Recipient of the 2018 <u>Penn Engineering Exceptional Service Award</u>
- Recipient of the 2019 <u>Littlejohn Scholars Summer Research Grant</u>
- **❖** 2019-20 <u>J.P. Eckert Fellow</u>
- ❖ 2020 inductee of the <u>CIS Max Mintz Undergraduate TA Hall of Fame</u>
- Recipient of the Summer 2020 TA Award for Excellence in Student Support with Distinction
- ♦ Honorable Mention for the <u>2021 Penn Engineering Outstanding Teaching Award</u>
- ❖ Carnegie Institute of Technology Dean's Fellow
- Selected to participate in the <u>2022 NextProf Pathfinder</u> workshop hosted by UMich and UCSD
- ❖ Completed the <u>Future Faculty Program</u> in Fall 2022 (Eberly Center for Teaching Excellence and Educational Innovation, Carnegie Mellon University)
- Recipient of the GEM Fellowship, with a sponsorship by MIT Lincoln Lab for Summer 2023
- ♦ UPenn SEAS Orientation Peer Adviser for Class of 2022 (CIS) and Class of 2023 (CMPE)
- ♦ Head of Hardware team for UPenn <u>PennApps</u> hackathon from Spring 2019 to Spring 2021, organized with <u>Major League Hacking</u> (MLH)
- ❖ 2022-25 CMU Robotics Club Officer